Munqaiz Wani

L&D Manager, Kyari Solutions pvt. ltd. (CAN JOIN NOW))

Summary

Market focused International Business Educated Professional with successful marketing, Business Planning, Strategic Management, Human Resource and Customer Relationship management Experience. Masters Dissertation on the Role of Islamic Banking in Britain. Firsthand experience of Recruiting, Legal Documentation and Legal Proceedings. Management experience in Branding, Product management and Human Resource and Finance. Working experience of FDCPA and worked in an environment adhering to Financial Crime Prevention (FCP) and Personal Account Dealing (PAD) Procedures.

Specialties

Management, Customer Service and Law

Experience

L&D Manager at Kyari solutions Pvt. Ltd

May 2014 - Present (1 year 3 months)

Plan, develop and implement strategy for HR management and development (including recruitment and selection policy/practices, discipline, grievance, counseling, pay and conditions, contracts, training and development, succession planning, moral and motivation, culture and attitude development, performance appraisal and quality management issues) Establish and maintain appropriate systems for measuring necessary aspects of HR Development. Liaise with other functional / departmental head so as to understand all necessary aspects and needs of HR development, and to ensure they are fully informed of HR objectives, purpose and achievement. Induction, Sales and Soft skills training to new and existing Employees. Regular training sessions like morning hurdle to keep the sales force updated. Audit and authenticate all documents related to legal, salary statements and distribution, policies etc. Plan for employee's performance appraisal; develop tools for appraisal, job evaluation and development Plan and direct for Trainings of employees including senior managers. Always available to HELP Sales

Manager Trainings at MetLife

May 2012 - May 2014 (2 years 1 month)

Training Branch Managers, Managers, Specified Personnel from Banks, FPc's and CSO's Of Jammu and Kashmir Bank Ltd. and Punjab National bank. Carrying out various Activities in banks for the promotion of the products updating and training all the above when something new comes into the picture. Besides that Field Visits, Cascading and giving presentations to various high bank officials to so that they can carry forward their business with ease.

customer Service Associate (British Gas) at Randstad UK

August 2011 - March 2012 (8 months)

Worked as both inbound and outbound executive for British Gas. Used to call customer's to change their energy meters. Besides that upselling, Cross selling and Customer service was the main aim of my job profile. Delaing in all kinds of payments over the phone and also dealing with complicated customer queries.

Business Customer Specialist (O2, Telefonica UK) at Randstad UK

December 2010 - July 2011 (8 months)

Proving customer Service to all business customer of O2. Working out their bills, finance, upgrades, new connections, network, payments, contracts, resigns etc. Cross-selling, up-selling, Promotions, retentions and making new customers for O2. Managing Customer contracts O2 partners, other network providers, Stores etc. Turning O2 customers into O2 fans.

Customer Service and Technical Advisor at Molson Coors Brewers

February 2008 - August 2010 (2 years 7 months)

Assisting Customers with their account information and while placing orders. Tracking logistic flow and handling the urgent shipment tasks.\ Moved from part time to full time. Cross-Selling, up-selling, promoting new products and giving customers variety to choose from rather than to stick with what he has got. Ensuring high end customer service with customer satisfaction approach.

Advocate at Jammu and Kashmir High Court

March 2006 - November 2007 (1 year 9 months)

Practised Law at various sub-District, District and High court in J&K Handling all kinds of matters including, Civil, Crime, and Property disputes. Handling company legal matters and replacing my senior's presence oftento address and redress the client issues and make appearances on my senior's behalf in courts. One of the highest paid and promising young lawyers in the high at that time.

Courses

MAIB, Cross Cultural Human Resource Management

Leeds Beckett Unix

Leeds Beckett University MAIB

Projects

Islamic Banking in UK

March 2009 to May 2009

Members: Munqaiz Wani

A laymans banking

Languages

Urdu (Limited working proficiency)

Hindi (Full professional proficiency)

Kashmiri (Limited working proficiency)

Punjabi (Elementary proficiency)

English (Full professional proficiency)

Skills & Expertise

Team Management

Management

Business Development

Business Strategy

Recruiting

CRM

Training

Business Planning

Human Resources

Strategic Planning

Customer Service

Time Management

Team Building

Sales

Leadership

Vendor Management

Customer Satisfaction

Marketing

Banking

Product Management

Process Improvement

Corporate Law

Family Law

Criminology

Education

Leeds Beckett University

MAIB, Cross Cultural Human Resource Management, 2008 - 2009

Grade: PASS

Activities and Societies: part of all social activities, member of students union, helped out new students at the time of joining as in representation of the university in front of new students and their parents, arranging campus visits, accomdation guidance etc

University of Kashmir

Bachelors; LL.B, Law; Criminal Law, 2003 - 2006

Activities and Societies: Activities include seminars, debates and Moot courts.I was a part of every activity in the University besides representing my University at the national level in Soccer, I had also played Cricket for the University.

Amar Singh College

Bachelors in Science (B.Sc); A' Levels, Chemistry, Zoology; Mathematics, English, 2000 - 2003 Activities and Societies: Attended every seminar, debate and group discussions held by the College. Represented College at various Sports including Cricket and Football.

Munqaiz Wani

L&D Manager, Kyari Solutions pvt. ltd. (CAN JOIN NOW))



Contact Munqaiz on LinkedIn